Anne Martindell Papers, 1898-2008 (bulk 1968-1990): Finding Aid MC203
Public Policy Papers
- Series 4: Subject Files, 1923-2008; 4 boxes
  The Subject Files series is primarily composed of documents relating to Martindell's personal activities and is arranged alphabetically. Included are materials detailing Martindell's education, from high school to a course taken at Princeton University in 1999, as well as correspondence and Freedom of Information Act requests regarding Federal Bureau of Investigation documents pertaining to Martindell, and a draft of a New Jersey legislature resolution regarding impeachment of Richard Nixon. There is also a scrapbook from a trip taken by Martindell in 1923. Materials include school records, correspondence, clippings, and notebooks.
  - Birthday, 1994; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Education, 1928-2002; 2 boxes
    - Mercer County Community College, 1998; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Princeton University (Civil War class), 1998-1999; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - St. Timothy's School, 1931; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Smith College, 1986-1989; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Smith College Graduation and Award, 1997-2002; 1 box (Box 32)
      Four folders of clippings and correspondence that document Martindell's return to Smith College to pursue her bachelor's degree between 1998 and 2002, as well as her receipt of a Remarkable Woman award at Smith in 1999. A few other clippings from the time period are also present.
    - Miscellaneous Records and Applications, 1928-1966; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1985-1987; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Impeachment, 1974; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Oral History Project, 1986-1991; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Veendam (Trip Scrapbook), 1923; 1 folder (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1964-2008; 1 box
    - General, 1964-1990 and undated, 3 folders (Box 29, Folder 1-3)
    - Clippings, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Notebook, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Anne Clark Martindell Memorial Program, 2008; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 6)
- Series 5: Photographs, 1929-2002; 2 boxes
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  This collection contains materials acquired from a Zip Disk. Researchers are responsible for meeting the technical requirements needed to access these materials, including any and all hardware and software.
  The Photograph series contains photographs, arranged alphabetically by subject, from Martindell's personal and professional lives. Included are photographs of Martindell with Jimmy Carter and George McGovern and from Martindell's state senate campaign, as well as publicity shots and photographs of her various travels. Researchers should note that a small number of photographs are available in the Memoirs series.
  - Ambassador, 1980; 1 box
    - New Zealand, circa 1980; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Tokelau Islands, circa 1980; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Antarctica, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Australia-New Zealand-United States Treaty (ANZUS), 1988; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Book, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Byrne, Brendan, 1974; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Boston Globe, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Carter, Jimmy, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Charles, Prince of Wales, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Clinton, William, 1994; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Democratic Presidential Delegation, 1972; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Hart, Gary, 1987; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - McGovern, George, 1972; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - New Zealand, dates not examined; 1 box
    - General, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Unidentified - Probably New Zealand, undated; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Office of Foreign Disaster Assistance (OFDA), circa 1977; 1 folder (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Personal, 1929-2001; 1 box
    - People, 1929-2001; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Places, undated; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Publicity, undated; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Professional, undated; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Queen's Service Order, undated; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Requests - Personal, 1970; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Rutgers, undated; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Senate, 1972-1975; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Smith College, 2000-2002; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Zip disk (JPG files), undated; 17 digital files; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Anne Martindell, 1971-1987 and undated, 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 11)
- Oversize Material, 1979-1981; 1 box
  Box 31 includes 3 folders of oversize material removed from the series listed above, including a reception book from the United States Embassy in New Zealand which was used during Martindell's time as Ambassador.
  For purposes of appropriate storage, the materials in this series are not arranged in any particular order.
  - Reception book from United States Embassy in New Zealand, 1979-1981; 1 box (Box 31)
  - Apgar Award, undated; 1 box (Box 31)
  - Correspondence from Judith Alpert, undated; 1 box (Box 31)